https://www.childrens.health.qld.gov.au/chq/privacy-statement/

Public health notices
Our Hospital and Health ServiceOur boardOur executiveOur vision and valuesOur performanceStrategies and plansPatient safetyLatest newsNewsYour storiesBlogMedia releasesOur Digital FutureHealth InformaticsTraining informationieMR resourcesQuick Reference Guides and WorkflowsVideosFact sheetsBusiness Continuity Procedures and Downtime resourcesFrequently asked questionsBusiness rulesOther resourcesSupport contactsNewsIntegrated care digital programPatient Online Portal – ArchivedSmart Referrals Reporting and Analytics CapabilityQH-Mater Information Sharing ProjectGP access to ‘The Viewer’Smart Referrals Workflow Solution (eRefer)Our charity and volunteer partnersPublic interest disclosuresDisclosure logGifts and benefits registerOur services
Find a service
Hospital services
Queensland Youth Cancer Service
How we can help
The Queensland Youth Advisory Group (YAG)
Our partners
Health professionals
Family and Community Place (Yarrabilba)
Community health services
Centre for Children’s Health and Wellbeing
Child Development Program
Child Health Service
Deadly Ears
Ellen Barron Family Centre
Good Start Program
Healthy Hearing Program
Primary School Nurse Health Readiness Program
School-based Youth Health Service
Mental health services
Our teams
Babies and young children (aged 0 to 4 years)
Kids (aged 5 to 11 years)
Teens (aged 12+)
For parents and carers
Music and mental health
Where to get help
Find your local CYMHS
Mental Health Act
Queensland Centre for Perinatal and Infant Mental Health
Generation Zero Suicide (GenZs)
Jacaranda Place
Queensland Poisons Information Centre
First aid
What is a poison?
Seasonal dangers
Poisons around the home
For parents and carers
Bites and stings
Plants and mushrooms (fungi) poisonous to people
Resources
Health professionals
Find a serviceHospital servicesCommunity health servicesCentre for Children’s Health and WellbeingHealthy KidsConnecting 2 UBaby’s first foodsHealthy Hearing ProgramScreeningMipla Binna — Our Ears family resourceQueensland Hearing Loss Family Support ServiceResourcesDeadly EarsMiddle ear diseaseDeadly Kids, Deadly FuturesReferralsResourcesEllen Barron Family CentreResponsive settling video seriesOur facilitiesFrequently asked questionsGood Start ProgramChild Development ProgramChild Health ServicePrimary School Nurse Health Readiness ProgramSchool-based Youth Health ServiceFamily and Community Place (Yarrabilba)Mental health servicesOur teamsBabies and young children (aged 0 to 4 years)Kids (aged 5 to 11 years)Teens (aged 12+)For parents and carersMusic and mental healthWhere to get helpFind your local CYMHSMental Health ActQueensland Centre for Perinatal and Infant Mental HealthZero to Four Child and Youth Mental Health ServiceZero to Four Family Support ServiceStrategy Unite-PIMH Telehealth ServicePerinatal and infant mental healthEmotional wellbeing for you and your childResources for familiesResources for health professionalsGovernanceNatural disaster resourcesWho else can helpGeneraration Zero Suicide (GenZs)Jacaranda PlaceQueensland Poisons Information CentreFirst aidWhat is a poison?Seasonal dangersSpringSummerAutumnWinterPoisons around the homePoisoning preventionBites and stingsPlants and mushrooms (fungi)ResourcesHealth professionalsQueensland Youth Cancer ServiceHow we can helpThe Queensland Youth Advisory Group (YAG)Our partnersHealth professionalsInformation for families Children’s health fact sheetsAntibiotic awarenessMedicinesCaring for your babyCPR Awareness ProgramSpecial support services for familiesAboriginal and Torres Strait Islander familiesPacific Islander and Maori familiesRefugee children and young peopleFoster childrenInterpreter ServicesPersonal health record (red book)Parents’ evaluation of development statusImmunisationMental health informationFinding a GPTelehealthHealth professionals
Find a service
General Practitioners hub
Management and referral guidelines
Queensland Paediatric Emergency Care
Referring patients
How to submit a referral
Referral forms
Eligibility requirements
Conferences and training
Children’s Advice and Transport Coordination Hub (CATCH)
Integrated care
Project ECHO
General Practice Liaison Program
Queensland Child and Youth Clinical Network
Queensland Paediatric Quality Council
Queensland Specialist Immunisation Service
Find a serviceManagement and referral guidelinesQueensland Paediatric Emergency CareReferring patientsSpecialist Online AdviceHow to submit a referralReferral formsEligibility requirementsCatchment areasFrequently asked questionsAntimicrobial StewardshipClinical guidelines (infection management)SepsisCentral nervous system infectionsEar, nose and throat (ENT) infectionsCardiac infectionsRespiratory infectionsGastro-intestinal infectionsUrinary tract infection (UTI)Skeletal, soft tissue and skin infectionsTropical infectious diseasesPerinatal and congenital infectionsNeonatal dosingSurgical antibiotic prophylaxisSpecialty guidelinesAllergy to antimicrobialsIntravenous (IV) to oral antimicrobial switchAntimicrobial restrictionsTherapeutic drug monitoring (TDM)HITH (Home Intravenous antibiotics)Clinical resourcesAntibiogramsE-learningAntibiotic Champion NetworkAbout Antimicrobial StewardshipStandards of Antimicrobial StewardshipPaediatric health resourcesDevelopments – a newsletter for referring GPsPaediatric Nutrition Screening ToolWheeze Action PlanABI resourcesPaediatric Optometry Alignment ProgramIntegrated careProject ECHO®HealthPathways – ArchivedGeneral Practice Liaison ProgramAccessing patient health informationChildren’s health fact sheetsOut-of-Home CareConferences and trainingQueensland Child and Youth Clinical NetworkQueensland Paediatric Quality CouncilQueensland Specialist Immunisation ServiceChildren’s Advice and Transport Coordination Hub (CATCH)Work for us Working at CHQHow to applyCurrent jobsEmployee benefitsRecruitment contactsLiving in BrisbaneNursing jobsNursing at Queensland Children’s HospitalWhat our nurses sayCareers in paediatric intensive careGet involved Consumer groupsFamily Advisory CouncilAccess QCHVolunteersDonationsRegister your interestShare your experienceContact us
Privacy statement
Home>CHQ>Privacy statement
Privacy statement
Children's Health Queensland
2017-06-23T11:15:18+00:00
Privacy statementQueensland has privacy legislation which applies to the Queensland public sector—the Information Privacy Act 2009 (IP Act). The IP Act contains privacy principles which set out how agencies may and must handle personal information. Personal information means any information about an identifiable person.
What happens to your personal information
Website privacy and security statementChildren’s Health Queensland (CHQ) is committed to protecting the privacy of our website users. We understand and appreciate that visitors to, and users of, this website, are concerned about their privacy and the confidentiality and security of information they provide to us.
As a general rule, we do not collect information that can directly identify you when you visit our site. When you visit our site to read or download information, our web measurement tool and Internet Service Providers record the following information only for statistical purposes:
your server and IP address
the name of the top level domain (for example, .gov, .com, .edu, .au)
the type of browser used
the date and time you accessed the site
the pages accessed and documents downloaded
the previous site you visited.
These statistics provide information to assist us to make improvements to the content and structure of our website.
We collect personal information via online forms or by email communications for the purposes of, for example, registration for community advisory groups.Email correspondenceYour email address details will not be added to a mailing list nor will we disclose these details to third parties without your consent, unless required by law. Email messages may be monitored by our information technology staff for system trouble-shooting and maintenance purposes.CookiesCookies are text files that a website can transfer to your computer when you access information on that site. Cookies allow websites to recognise you as you browse their website.
Children’s Health Queensland uses Google Analytics to gather statistics about how the website is accessed. Google Analytics uses cookies to gather information for the purpose of providing statistical reporting. The cookies do not collect information that can directly identify you.
The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers located outside of Australia. No personally identifying information is recorded or provided to Google.
Information gathered using the Google Analytics cookie is used for the purpose of determining:
the number of visitors to the CHQ website
how visitors arrive at the CHQ website, for example, did they type the address in directly, follow a link from another webpage, or arrive via a search engine?
the number of times each page is viewed and for how long
time and date of visits
geographical location of visitors
information about what browsers are used to view the CHQ website and the operating system of the computers or devices
whether these browsers supports Java and Flash
the speed of the user’s internet connection.
This information is used to refine and improve the CHQ online service delivery and in turn the community’s online experience.
View a Google Analytics example reportPublic recordsEmail correspondence, blog comments and information provided via webforms can constitute public records and can be retained as required by the Public Records Act 2002 and other relevant legislation.Use and disclosureWe will only use personal information collected via our website for the purposes for which it was given to us and/or for related, internal management purposes.
We do not disclose your personal information to other government agencies, organisations or anyone else unless one of the following applies:
you consented to the disclosure
you would have a reasonable expectation that your personal information would be disclosed
it is required or authorised by law
it will prevent or lessen a serious threat to somebody’s life or health; and
the disclosure is reasonably necessary for a law enforcement activity.
SecurityWe take strong precautions to protect the personal information we hold concerning you from loss, unauthorised access, use, modification or disclosure, and against other misuse. However, please be aware we do not provide a mechanism for securing the transmission of information across the Internet.Links to other sitesThis website contains links to other websites. Children’s Health Queensland is not responsible for the content and privacy practices of other websites.LegislationQueensland legislation which provides privacy and confidentiality protections for personal information include:
Information Privacy Act 2009
Information Privacy Regulation 2009
Hospital and Health Boards Act 2011
Hospital and Health Boards Regulation 2012
Amend your personal informationApplications for access and/or amendment of personal information may be sought under:
Information Privacy Act 2009
Information Privacy Regulation 2009
Right to Information Act 2009
Right to Information Regulation 2009
Queensland Health’s ‘Health Information: Disclosure and Access Policy’
If there is information in your health record that is incorrect or which you do not agree with, you can apply for it to be amended under the Information Privacy Act 2009. You will need to provide details of why the information may be inaccurate, incomplete, out of date or misleading, For more information contact the Manager, Clinical Information Access Unit using the contact details below.Contacts or complaints about privacyIf you would like more information or would like to make a complaint about privacy please do so using the following details:
Mail
Privacy Officer
Health Information Access
Children’s Health Queensland
PO Box 3474
South Brisbane QLD 4101
e: CHQ_HIA@health.qld.gov.au
t: 07 3068 4842 (within Australia), +61 7 3068 4842 (International)
GP access to ‘The Viewer’
Smart Referrals Workflow Solution (eRefer)
Register your interest for consumer engagement opportunities
Brisbane general paediatrics referral catchments – full list
Clinical guidelines (infection management)
Urinary tract infection (UTI)
Therapeutic drug monitoring (TDM)
HITH (Home Intravenous antibiotics)
Children’s Advice and Transport Coordination Hub (CATCH)
Personal health record (red book)
Family and Community Place (Yarrabilba)
Mental health services
Our teams
Babies and young children (aged 0 to 4 years)
Kids (aged 5 to 11 years)
Teens (aged 12+)
Generaration Zero Suicide (GenZs)
Queensland Poisons Information Centre
First aid
What is a poison?
Plants and mushrooms (fungi)
Resources
Health professionals
Queensland Youth Cancer Service
How we can help
The Queensland Youth Advisory Group (YAG)
Is your feedback:*About this pageCompliments, complaints or suggestionsYour feedback/comment about this page:*Your name:*Your email:*
Please submit your comments on our share your experience section.CommentsThis field is for validation purposes and should be left unchanged.
This iframe contains the logic required to handle Ajax powered Gravity Forms.
X
COVID-19 latest updates
| COVID-19 changes to visiting the QCH
